The SCOAN Sunday Service
- Hallelujah!
- Amen!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to take you up on a special issue today.
I realised people don’t give anymore.
When you meet people today, they will say they have nothing or little.
Giving reshapes our destiny.
Tell your neighbour.
When you give with all your heart, not giving for selfish, classical or material reasons,
it is reshaping your destiny.
People don't give today.
They say, "I don't have. I have little for my family. It is difficult for me to share, to part with it."
- Hallelujah!
- Amen!
We take our reading from the Book of Luke 16.
“Jesus told his disciples: ‘There was a rich man
whose manager was accused of wasting his possessions'".
I'm taking reading from verse 1.
"'So he called him in and asked him, ‘What is this I hear about you?
Give an account of your management because you cannot be manager any longer.’"
That is a boss speaking to his staff.
“’The manager said to himself, ‘What shall I do now?’”
Let's go to the proof text - verse 10.
“Whoever can be trusted with very little can also be trusted with much,
and whoever is dishonest with little will also be dishonest with much."
Think about that.
“So if you have not been trustworthy in handling worldly wealth, who will trust you with true riches?
And if you have not been trustworthy with someone else’s property,
who will give you property of your own?”
Take your time to read 1 Corinthians 14:16,
and the Book of Mark 12:42-44
and the Book of Matthew 25:22-24.
Here we are today with numerous challenges – stagnation, career failure, affliction – just name it.
Glory be to God – there is hope.
The same God who was with us yesterday will be with us today.
Tell your neighbour.
That is hope.
The same God who was with us yesterday will be with us today.
Tell your neighbour, "There is hope".
I cannot hear you.
There is hope.
The same God who was with us yesterday will be with us today.
That is hope.
This is why you should be calm.
There is no need of worrying yourself; leave it for God.
From the Book of Mark 12:42-44
and the Book of Matthew 25:22-24, which I have given you,
and 1 Corinthians 14:16.
GOD CARES ABOUT LITTLE
We are in the season of little.
No matter what you have.
The richest man in the world today will tell you that the things are little; it is not as it was before.
Businesses are becoming little, your income is becoming little, your strength - also the same.
Many people - from 3 bedrooms to 2 bedrooms.
Many begin to sell some of their property to still stand for the future.
Tell your neighbour, “We are in the season of little”.
It is a season.
Time for everything.
You may say it is an attack - no, it is not an attack, it is a season, it is everywhere.
Tell your neighbour, “God cares about little”.
One thing we must know today – we all believe that we can only give out of abundance.
Because we are used to giving only what we do not need,
what we have used, the left-over in our store or garage.
Somebody runs to you, "Please, help me!"
Instead of giving something you need, something your life depends on, something you cherish,
you open your store and give something you have used, something you do not need,
the left-over from your store.
You open your store and say, "This is a good tyre for you".
If it is a good tyre for you, why is it not good for you?
The left-over in our store; we are used to that.
Think back - what we have been giving to people.
They cherish it because they have no choice.
Whatever we give out of little, it means a lot to us because it attracts God’s attention.
This is why Jesus was watching the poor widow – because He cares about little.
He was watching the poor widow, while other rich people were going.
He was looking at the poorest woman among the crowd to see how much,
how she would part out of that little.
Tell your neighbour,
Whatever you give out of little, it means a lot to you because it attracts God’s attention.
If you don’t know how much you need God in the small things,
you cannot know how much you need God in the big things
because everything big starts little.
If something big starts big, it calls for concern.
How many of us here can tell me how much you need God to sit down or to stand up?
You don't need God to sit down because you can sit down.
No single person can tell me they rely on God’s strength to sit down.
No one can tell me he or she relies on God to stand up.
You want to stand up, you meditate in your heart, "In Jesus' name..."
You want to sit down, "In Jesus' name..." -
you can't do that!
Tell your neighbour,
If you don’t know how much you need God in the small things,
you cannot know how much you need Him in the big things.
This is why your relationship is in shambles.
There is cause for concern in your relationship with God
because you don’t know how much you need God.
Even to close your eyes, you need God.
To comb your hair, you need God.
To eat, you need God.
To dress up, you need God.
To walk, you need God.
To talk, you need God but you ignore that, do that on your own
because you believe you don’t need God to do all those things
but you only need God for your situation – to help you, heal you, prosper you.
This is just it.
If you don’t know how much you need God in the small things
such as to talk, look, walk, dress up, comb your hair or greet,
you will not know how much you need God to settle your situation.
Don’t forget you were once an embryo in your mother’s womb.
See what you have become today.
If you ignore your young, definitely you will ignore your old.
Please, pray without ceasing.
Constantly pray in your heart – in hymns, spiritual songs and making melodies in your heart.
Are you doing that now?
Are you in that business now, or you are just looking at me?
If you are just looking at me, your heart will be telling you a different thing.
While you are looking at me, it would be telling you, "Don't mind the man; it is difficult to do.
OK, anyway, God will help me."
Your heart will be saying different things, while you are looking at me.
You must get hold of your heart; control your heart.
When you are able to control your heart, then you will know how much you need God in small things.
When you want to stand; if you are in the meditation business -
if you want to stand, you say, "In Jesus' name. Thank You."
You are going, "Thank You, Jesus".
You want to stop, "Thank You, Jesus".
You want to greet, "Thank You, Jesus"
Because you are into that in your heart.
In the Book of Matthew 25:22-24,
God is constantly putting us to the test in the small things.
If we fail to bless others with the little God has given us, we may never grow.
That is why some of us remain in the same position.
If you don’t know how much you need God in the small things such as to walk, talk, stand or sit,
you will continue to have certain occasions for prayer.
That is why you have certain occasions..., "3 o'clock - I need to break my fasting, I need to go and pray."
Why a certain occasion for prayer?
This is why satan keeps getting that opportunity to get you.
The Bible says a break in prayer is a break in faith and a break is faith is a break with God.
Tell your neighbour,
A break in prayer is a break in faith; a break in faith is a break with God.
Tell your neighbour again,
Certain occasions for prayer is a break with God.
The little time you have a break with God, satan gets you.
When you know how much you need God, you will pray without ceasing – pray continuously.
Prayer is the key
Prayer is the master key
Jesus started with prayer and ended with prayer
That is all.
Jesus started here and ended here;
He started with prayer, all throughout, and ended with prayer.
Why certain occasion for prayer?
Why is your life different from Jesus’ life?
He is our role model.
He started with prayer and ended with prayer but it seems you have certain occasions for prayer
because you don’t know how much you need Him in the small things.
Prayer is the key
Prayer is the master key
Jesus started with prayer and ended with prayer
Can you see why you are very accessible to satan?
He can get you anytime and he can drop you anytime.
He knows how to get you.
He knows when you are not with God.
He knows when you have a break with God.
Each time you have a break with God, he gets you.
Are you in the business of prayer right now?
Each time you have a break, you drop the master key to loose and bind.
Constantly pray in your heart.
Why in my heart?
Because your heart is the communication point, contact point.
That is all.
If Jesus is coming to you, it is to your heart.
It is the landing point.
He will land before talking to you.
You don't hear the voice of God here.
Someone will say, "I can hear this; God says this, that" - no, God doesn't say here.
Here, our heart - contact point, communication point.
Our heart is the prayer room; our heart is the altar.
Constantly pray in your heart in hymns and spiritual songs.
What is a hymn?
I have given you; you have hymns, songs...
All the way to Calvary He went for me...
In your heart.
If your heart is talking, your lips should not move.
Keep busy with that - there are many songs for you.
You drop that after a while, "Locate me in Your mercy, Lord" - in your heart.
After a while you drop that, say "Take more of me, give me more of You".
This is the route to God, the channel to God.
Your contribution to others – see it as an assignment from God.
Whatever you give, see it as an assignment from God.
Whatever you do, "Excuse me, can I help you? OK, thank you" - see it as an assignment from God.
Failing them is failing God.
When you see it as an assignment from God, you will not wait to receive reward.
Tomorrow you meet the person you helped, you will now begin to say, "Look at this woman I helped;
she didn't even greet me - see her. Madam, you don't know me?
I was the one who helped you yesterday. You can't even say 'thank you.'"
If it was an assignment from God, you would not wait for the reward.
See it as an assignment from God.
Once you do that, God will reward you; God is the Rewarder.
God is so much concerned about little.
That is why He was watching the poor widow.
God is so much concerned about your little possessions.
He wants you to grow.
How can you grow when you are not part with others?
Whatever you give out of little, it means so much.
It is easy to part with little than much.
The rich cannot give what their life depends on
but the poor give what their life depends on, no matter how little.
So, there is no excuse now that you have little – that is the best time to give.
Tell your neighbour,
little...
Ask your neighbour,
You have little?
God is so much concerned about your little possessions because He wants you to grow.
When you part with little, consider it as an assignment from God.
Don’t accept someone coming to you to thank you; it will affect your gift.
Someone would say, "Thank you very much for what you have given me yesterday" -
it will affect what you have given him.
If somebody comes to you and says, "I want to thank you
for what you have given me yesterday - it really helped",
"Ha! I want to thank you for receiving it."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Because you are reshaping your destiny.
Thanking people after a gift is a "culture", it is a tradition, but spiritually, it has a comma.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to leave you here.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT ROBERT BEGIER 03/10/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 26/10/2018